Kostadis Roussos: Hello, George.
Kostadis Roussos: How you doing, man?
george: Good.
Kostadis Roussos: How was… how was Greece?
george: Very nice.
Kostadis Roussos: Where'd you go?
george: Greets and Rafina.
Kostadis Roussos: And where?
george: Rafina.
Kostadis Roussos: Awesome.
george: Doesn't.
Kostadis Roussos: That's an interesting place to go.
george: Yeah, cause my cousins have a… apartment there.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: When I was a kid, Rafina was very far away from Athens, because it hadn't been built out until there.
Kostadis Roussos: Right, so when I was a kid, the Rafina was always… I always thought of Rafina as very far away, because that's where my…
Kostadis Roussos: My family in downtown Athens would go for the summer.
george: Yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: Right?
Kostadis Roussos: And,
Kostadis Roussos: It was a bit of an adventure back then, because they didn't have a car, so we'd have to take the bus.
george: I took the bus once. It took, like, an hour.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, but this is, like, you know, back in the day, right?
Kostadis Roussos: So… s…
Kostadis Roussos: So we would arrive there, and we would go swimming, right? That was where we would go swimming for the summer.
Kostadis Roussos: So, when I turned, so I did my first marathon 10 years ago, 10, 12 years ago.
Kostadis Roussos: And I'm, Yes, I have joined.
Kostadis Roussos: And Nick's on the wrong Zoom.
Kostadis Roussos: So, so we arrive in Athens.
Kostadis Roussos: If I rev… Hello, Nicholas.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, no problem, man.
Kostadis Roussos: So I arrive in Athens, so we would arrive there. I was telling the story, I arrive to do my marathon, so I show up in… show up in Athens, and I get the map, right, for the Athens marathon.
Kostadis Roussos: And I look… I hadn't actually looked at the distance up until that time, right? I'd trained for the marathon, but I hadn't actually looked… you know, 42 kilometers is a large distance, but you don't realize how big it is.
Kostadis Roussos: And so I'm looking at the map, and I realize that Marathon is 10 kilometers away from Raffina, which in my mind was already a very far away.
Kostadis Roussos: I was like, holy fuck, what am I doing?
Thomas Kolivakis: You start in Athens, and you finish at Athena.
Kostadis Roussos: No, no, you start in Marathon, which is 10 kilometers.
Thomas Kolivakis: You do the whole…
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, I did the whole marathon, right? So you start in marathon.
Kostadis Roussos: Right?
Kostadis Roussos: And there's actually a detour to go see the, where they buried the dead from the Battle of Marathon, right? So you start in Marathon, you take a left, do the detour, go to the beach, and then go back.
Kostadis Roussos: And, it's, it's a crazy… it's a… it's a real… if you're gonna ever do a marathon, I recommend it, because it's a very fun marathon. You start off in…
Kostadis Roussos: You start off in the hinterland of Atiki, right?
Kostadis Roussos: past, past Rafina, past everything. You go through farmland, And then you start climbing.
Kostadis Roussos: And then you get into downtown Athens, and then there's, like, a 10km downhill until you hit Kolonaki.
Kostadis Roussos: And you finish in the,
Kostadis Roussos: The stadium where the first marathon… the first modern marathon finished.
Thomas Kolivakis: Not too hot?
Kostadis Roussos: That's in November?
Thomas Kolivakis: I don't remember.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, so… so…
Kostadis Roussos: two points, it can be… it can be brutally hot. One year I did it, and it was, like, I almost died of a heart attack. The… but it's in John… but the other years, it was so cold that people were freezing.
Kostadis Roussos: So… It depends, but in general, it's actually quite pleasant.
Kostadis Roussos: My favorite marathon story is there's this couple, they're about my age now, but they were a little bit older than me, and they're on their phone, talking to their son… they took a break, and they're talking to their son who finished… who was competing in the… who's competing for the national team in the Athens marathon, and they're talking to him about how did he do?
Kostadis Roussos: We're, like, 3-4 hours away from finished, and, you know, they're talking to their son who finished, like, finished.
Kostadis Roussos: And I'm, like, going, that is quintessential Greek parents.
Thomas Kolivakis: Prior to do one in 10 years.
Kostadis Roussos: What?
Kostadis Roussos: Dude, you should totally do one. It's like, the three of you should do one.
Kostadis Roussos: Nicholas goes, yeah, I'm not that stupid.
Thomas Kolivakis: And my friend did one, like, a week ago, just to, like, do his cardio.
Kostadis Roussos: Really?
Thomas Kolivakis: And Montreal is… Started running.
Kostadis Roussos: He started… did he do the full marathon, or…
Thomas Kolivakis: Yeah, the 42K.
Kostadis Roussos: Shit. How old is he?
Thomas Kolivakis: He's a mage.
Kostadis Roussos: 17 or… you're 17 or 18?
Thomas Kolivakis: Actually, he's 16, he's 16, I'm 17.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Because in Greece, they don't let you do it until you… they don't actually let you in the US register until you're 18.
Thomas Kolivakis: No, it wasn't an official marathon, you just did it by himself.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, okay, okay, okay, I was gonna say… that's why I asked, because I can… yeah, no, totally.
Kostadis Roussos: And they don't… because of liability, they don't let people do it. They don't want to deal with… not… not the liability of people getting hurt.
Kostadis Roussos: With the liability of having underage kids running in a race with lots of adults.
Kostadis Roussos: In an unsupervised manner.
Kostadis Roussos: Great.
Kostadis Roussos: So, people are like… the guy, the organizers don't want to deal with that.
Kostadis Roussos: Because, you know, all it takes is one kid to have something bad happen, and, you know, all hell breaks loose.
Kostadis Roussos: As you probably know. Alright, so, first of all, it's great to be back.
Kostadis Roussos: My favorite campaign ever. Like, I never really thought this would be… I would have this much fun. Okay, so a couple things. You are… let me just, so I did something, hopefully, that you'll find interesting.
Kostadis Roussos: So I wrote… I had… I admit it, I had AI,
Kostadis Roussos: You should sit. Do you see it?
Kostadis Roussos: Roll20?
Kostadis Roussos: Do you see… do you say the Ledger of Outstanding Business?
Thomas Kolivakis: I'm logged in.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, so if you log in, you'll see it.
Thomas Kolivakis: I see it.
Kostadis Roussos: Huh?
Thomas Kolivakis: Pop here, yep.
Kostadis Roussos: You see it?
Thomas Kolivakis: Yes.
Kostadis Roussos: George, I don't think you're yet on Rule 20, if you can get there.
george: It's loaded.
Kostadis Roussos: Why did your computer, man, it's so slow.
Kostadis Roussos: Thomas?
Kostadis Roussos: Why, why do you not help your brother?
Kostadis Roussos: George?
Thomas Kolivakis: He has a new laptop, you should use it.
Kostadis Roussos: George, do you use your new laptop, or do you still use your old laptop?
george: I'm using my desktop.
Kostadis Roussos: Ugh.
Kostadis Roussos: Nick, were you able to get in?
Nicholas Roussos: Oh, whoop.
Thomas Kolivakis: For some reason, like, everything… the… the…
Thomas Kolivakis: The thing in the middle, the ledger of outstanding business, like, the, the, the…
Thomas Kolivakis: The light is, like, completely dumb.
Kostadis Roussos: Well, okay, so, just so you know, I have… that's the… if you click on… there's a Google Doc link at the very top, I will put the Google Doc link.
Kostadis Roussos: Here we go, I'll put the Google Talk link in the chat so that you guys have it as well.
Kostadis Roussos: Let me just do that as well.
Thomas Kolivakis: Okay, okay.
Kostadis Roussos: It's… the conceit is that I had AI write it as if it was Zephyr keeping track of notes.
Thomas Kolivakis: Hmm.
Kostadis Roussos: So, it basically goes through all the things that you guys have done, and tells you what's going on.
Kostadis Roussos: What quests you have, So that you…
Thomas Kolivakis: Yes.
Kostadis Roussos: So, it kind of tells you, you know, The Ledger of Outstanding Business.
Kostadis Roussos: Kept by Zephyr, Chief of Operations, the Obsidian Edge, because somebody has to, and the cleric has declared bookkeeping beneath him.
Kostadis Roussos: So…
Thomas Kolivakis: And it's using the Notebook LM.
Kostadis Roussos: No, no, I've got a whole pipeline of… I'm happy to talk to you guys about it afterwards, but I have a whole technical pipeline for this. It's,
Kostadis Roussos: A notebook OM was so… was the starting point of me building a whole friggin' flamer… flamer.
Kostadis Roussos: So the important point is owed to management.
Kostadis Roussos: And finish business down here, and our own business.
Kostadis Roussos: And things nobody's paying for us.
Kostadis Roussos: Gonna give you a feel for what's going on.
Kostadis Roussos: Boom.
Kostadis Roussos: And I will just, go to Jam Assistant and read you the…
Kostadis Roussos: short summary of what was going on, and we'll jump in, alright? This should keep… this should give you an idea of what… all the… all the open quests.
Kostadis Roussos: If there's something wrong, it's… remember, Zephyr takes bad notes.
Kostadis Roussos: That's my… that's my inc… that's my in-canon way of saying, if there's a mistake, AI hallucinated, tell me, and blame Zephyr.
Kostadis Roussos: These are Zephyr.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright. The party escaped from the Hall of Verdigris proved… the party's escape from the Hall of Verdigris proved both harrowing and revealing. After Zephyr was lured by the mental suggestion into acidic, sentient pool, Zinnia leapt in without hesitation to drag him free, while Sequoia made the same mistake twice before scrambling clear.
Kostadis Roussos: Calmer deduced that the entity in the water could plant thoughts in their minds, a fact made more sinister when the party later raided Brother Eelrich Vane's chambers and discovered his ritual texts.
Kostadis Roussos: Strongly implied he had always known about the pool's living nature. They stripped his quarter of scrolls, ritual tasks on elemental water, a bronze mace, a golden pearl ring, and potions of water breathing, leaving Vane with a pointed warning.
Kostadis Roussos: Before returning to their lair to rest. There, Calmer formalized the group's new hierarchy, appointing Zinnia to lead intelligence, Zephyr to manage day-to-day operations, and Sequoia to handle valuables, while declaring spiritual matters as a sole concern.
Kostadis Roussos: The rest was interrupted by the arrival of Lucius Graeme, a cheerful middleman, sent by Barkinar.
Kostadis Roussos: Barkinar, bearing fine wine, healing potions, and a trust of enchanted goods. Sequoia and Zephyr each acquired enchanted blades, though the most coveted money items remained out of reach.
Kostadis Roussos: Giving you sharp motivation to plunder deeper into the temple. Armed with the knowledge that the trolls could be only permanently killed by fire, the party recruited Vurakhal, a fire salamander who communicated through their sentient sword Frostbrand, and set out to clear the troll air.
Kostadis Roussos: After bypassing a chained owlbear, they wisely chose to leave it alone. Sequoia and Zephyr launched a devastating surprise assault on two trolls feasting on fallen soldiers.
Kostadis Roussos: The fight turned brutal when one troll sprouted extra limbs and left Sequoia gravely wounded, but Vurakhal's searing heat aura denied the treachers their regeneration and turned the tide.
Kostadis Roussos: Pressing further through a secret door, Zinnia discovered… the party found the troll chieftain's grotesque chamber, walls plastered with filtened bones, furniture built from skeleton remains.
Kostadis Roussos: and executed a faultless coordinated strike, with Zephyr tripping the massive creature and Sequoia killing it in a single, perfectly placed blow before it could react.
Kostadis Roussos: The chieftain's horde yielded gold, platinum, a ring of fire resistance, a healing potion, and a magical wood totem that permanently turned a nearby desk vivid pink.
Kostadis Roussos: Right, so you have a token that changes color?
Kostadis Roussos: Pushing onward, calmer bluffed 20 bold pieces out of a group of air temple bugbears who had quietly claimed former Water Temple territory, and the session ended with the party stepping into a ruined reception hall.
Kostadis Roussos: Only for Sequoia to realize, with cold certainty, that the decorated Minotaur seated on the central throne was very much
Kostadis Roussos: alive.
Kostadis Roussos: Alrighty.
Kostadis Roussos: Let me just do one thing…
Kostadis Roussos: This is something… Interactive…
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, I'm sorry.
Kostadis Roussos: But… Alright, okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Alrighty, and in 20… And…
Kostadis Roussos: I… I hope you… I hope you guys get… get… are… find… if you guys find the, summary useful, I hope… I hope you find it useful.
Kostadis Roussos: I will create.
Thomas Kolivakis: Where's the summary?
Kostadis Roussos: No, no, the, oh, the, the, the, the summary,
Kostadis Roussos: I'll send you a link to the summary. It's not my perfectly generated one, so… but it's good enough.
Kostadis Roussos: It's got some spelling mistakes.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, I'll just send it to you.
Kostadis Roussos: I put it there. I put it in the chat. Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: And it's got a few errors, I haven't had a chance to clean everything up.
Kostadis Roussos: I was, too busy fixing my pipeline. Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: There we go.
Kostadis Roussos: Already.
Kostadis Roussos: Facing the Minotaur.
Kostadis Roussos: Hello? Pardon me?
Kostadis Roussos: Okie dokie.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, so you've discovered there is a Minotaur here.
Kostadis Roussos: Just to remind you what it says…
Kostadis Roussos: Just to remind you of the description…
Kostadis Roussos: This 40 by 50 foot chamber was evidently one in which new arrivals were hoisted to the delights of the temple. At least, this is what the wall murals depict. Few pieces of battered furniture, couches, chairs, and stands remain along the walls. In the center of a room is a shallow pool, its fountains apparently stopped and decorative.
Kostadis Roussos: stopped, and that means that it's not pouring. And the decorative statue of a minotaur sitting on a throne, much dirtied. Several skeletons lie about the place, and some awed skulls and bones as well. Mostly humans, but some humanoids as well.
Kostadis Roussos: None of them, none of the many cresits and wall sconces are lit. No torches remain, so the only light is the light that you guys are bringing into your room, into the room.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: So, what would you… you… Sequoia, you've discovered that it's a Minotaur. The Minotaur has not yet seen you. What would you like to do?
Nicholas Roussos: Get back to people.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, well, you kind of peeked through the door and saw that he was alive, so you kind of noticed it before he noticed you.
Kostadis Roussos: So, you close the door behind you, and Minotaur still has not noticed you.
Kostadis Roussos: You have a couple of choices, right? Remember, you're the big bosses at the end of the game, so nominally, this guy now works for you.
Kostadis Roussos: Or you could kill him and take his treasure.
Thomas Kolivakis: thinks she works for us.
Kostadis Roussos: I said nominally, remember, these are chaotic evil creatures.
Thomas Kolivakis: Does he speak in common?
Kostadis Roussos: He speaks abyssal.
Kostadis Roussos: Which I believe you speak.
Thomas Kolivakis: Yeah, I speak of this.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Thomas Kolivakis: No, I speak under common.
Kostadis Roussos: Don't speak abyssal?
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, does anybody have… does, Calmer have comprehend Languages?
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, you know who speaks Abyssal? I bet.
Kostadis Roussos: The fire salamander.
Kostadis Roussos: Cool.
Thomas Kolivakis: Can we leave the room and come back, or…
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, I mean… So, anyway, so that…
Kostadis Roussos: Let me just see what…
Kostadis Roussos: No, he doesn't speak abyssal either, so nobody… but, you know, maybe… maybe you could sort of sign yourselves way there. I mean, it's… it's up to you guys, like, how would you like to handle it?
Thomas Kolivakis: Alright, I'll tell him… We're your boss.
Kostadis Roussos: Do you want to bring Calmer in front, dressed as the Earth Cleric?
Thomas Kolivakis: Yeah.
Thomas Kolivakis: I'm also boss.
Kostadis Roussos: You're gonna… I'm gonna say, okay, so, Sequoia, you all good with this plan?
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Let me just see what, let me just…
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: So… You walk in with Calmer, right?
Kostadis Roussos: And you announce… You're the boss, right?
Kostadis Roussos: Turns out the Minotaur really hates the leadership of this place.
Kostadis Roussos: And is kind of enraged.
Kostadis Roussos: So you'll either have to kill it, or try to beat it down a little bit, and try to talk some sense into it.
Kostadis Roussos: So we will roll for initiative first.
Kostadis Roussos: Let's just do that.
Nicholas Roussos: 11.
george: 24.
Kostadis Roussos: Turn.
Kostadis Roussos: So, Xenia24… Sequoia 11… Is that fair?
Thomas Kolivakis: It's… sorry.
Thomas Kolivakis: God.
Thomas Kolivakis: 21.
Kostadis Roussos: Calmer, just use commas, default remote cassette.
Kostadis Roussos: on her knife.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, oh, I don't forget his initiative.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, let me just do this, guys.
Kostadis Roussos: 10?
Kostadis Roussos: Now, let's see if he surprises you.
Kostadis Roussos: This is, stealth. See, stealth? He's got a very bad stealth. Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, D20.
Kostadis Roussos: Is anybody's passive perception below 15?
george: polluter.
Thomas Kolivakis: It…
Kostadis Roussos: You're below 8, that's your passive perception.
Thomas Kolivakis: I love him.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, so… What about you, Sequoia?
Nicholas Roussos: My passive perception is 16. Not… no, not, not 16, sorry.
Nicholas Roussos: ted.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, what about you, Zephyr,
george: I have 17.
Nicholas Roussos: I rolled initiative on the wrong, character sheet, sorry.
Nicholas Roussos: 11, still.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, well, nothing changed.
Kostadis Roussos: By the way…
Nicholas Roussos: No.
Kostadis Roussos: By the way, if you guys want to help me, when you click your character, and then click initiative, it automatically adds it to the intern order.
Kostadis Roussos: So if you hit the D&D Beyond… when you click your character and then click the D&D Beyond Initiative button, it'll automatically do that. It'll save us some time, just keep that in mind.
Kostadis Roussos: If you don't remember, no big deal, I can still manually do it. Alright, so, Zephyr…
Kostadis Roussos: And Sequoia are surprised.
Kostadis Roussos: Calmer and Zinnia are not.
Kostadis Roussos: The mon- the Minotaur attacks Zephyr.
Kostadis Roussos: Why? Because… Zephyr, announced that he was the boss.
Thomas Kolivakis: No.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, so does he move 10 feet?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, he loses it 10 feet from here to here. Just measure.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, it's definitely 10 feet.
Kostadis Roussos: It's definitely 10 feet. He… the… okay, and then it hits you with its gore attack.
Kostadis Roussos: Right?
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, and it's gonna rule recklessly, so… Which means…
Kostadis Roussos: Except I did not rule correctly.
Kostadis Roussos: And let me just make this public, okay, alright, so…
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, so plan. So, RD… RD.
Kostadis Roussos: Hold on.
Kostadis Roussos: 124, that is a hit.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, you take.
Kostadis Roussos: 7 points of damage, wow, that was pretty bad.
Kostadis Roussos: That was really, really bad. And then you take a…
Kostadis Roussos: Like, why did I even bother rolling that?
Kostadis Roussos: Another 10 points of damage.
Kostadis Roussos: And, you, must succeed, roll a DC-14 saving throw.
Thomas Kolivakis: Of what? Dexterity?
Kostadis Roussos: Data strength.
Thomas Kolivakis: Yay.
Thomas Kolivakis: One.
Kostadis Roussos: You rolled a 1. Alright, so you are knocked prone, you are knocked against here, and you are prone.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: He moves there to… that's his reach.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, he moves there to keep beating you, because he hates you so much.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Because he… he hates… he hates the management here.
Kostadis Roussos: Zephyr, you were surprised. Sequoia, you were surprised.
Kostadis Roussos: Zinnia, you're up.
george: Good.
george: I'll attack it with his armor class.
Kostadis Roussos: 19.
george: 19.
george: Shit.
george: Okay…
george: I do 12 points of damage.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
george: my bonus attack.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, sounds good.
george: I miss…
Kostadis Roussos: You miss? Alright, 12 points of damage?
george: Yep.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, could you move your guy to where you're located?
george: Where am I?
Kostadis Roussos: Here, you should… you should… you're down here.
george: Love it.
Kostadis Roussos: Like, just play somewhere you are, you can just play some here if you want.
george: Slowly again.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, we'll put him over… we'll put you over here, so that gives Sequoia a chance to move into attack. Alright, Calmer is also not surprised.
Kostadis Roussos: What does Calmer do?
Kostadis Roussos: What do you want Calmer to do? Do you want him to try to talk to this guy, or, you know, beat him down a little bit before you guys talk to him?
Kostadis Roussos: He turns to, he turns to Zinnia as the head of secret… of, secret operations. What should he do?
Kostadis Roussos: Zinnia.
Kostadis Roussos: Calmer… Calmer needs some advice.
george: On what?
Kostadis Roussos: Should he kill… try to kill this creature, or talk to him?
george: I think talking would be weird.
Nicholas Roussos: Talk to it, man.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, so… You will.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, let me just, just, do you want me to talk? Alright, so we will talk.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, let me see what his persuasion is.
Kostadis Roussos: your roles.
Kostadis Roussos: He, intimidation or persuasion?
george: Sure.
Kostadis Roussos: I'll go with the persuasion.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
george: Yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: What did he rule?
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, he rules at 21.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: The, the creature, stares at Calmer, and, like, with his axe, still ready to… to hit him.
Kostadis Roussos: And… points to Zephyr with a clear indication that he views Zephyr as eating material.
Thomas Kolivakis: Just protect me.
Kostadis Roussos: What?
Thomas Kolivakis: Protect me, please.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, okay, so he, he's, he's kind of, he's willing to negotiate, so,
Kostadis Roussos: Hold on, let me get… there's a dog that needs something, give me a sec.
Kostadis Roussos: The anxiety level was off to a bundle in the month.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, Zinnia, you're up.
Kostadis Roussos: So, do you wanna… so the creature is… might be willing to listen if you have… if you can make him an offer.
Kostadis Roussos: You, you, you're up now. Yes. Calmer got him to, like, pause before he started relentlessly trying to kill him, so you, Zephyr, and Sequoia could try to make him an offer. I'll give you guys… you can use your actions to try to persuade, intimidate.
george: Of a bad persuasion.
george: I have bad persuasion, annotated invitation.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, so what you could do is you could try to get… Zephyr, what's your persuasion or intimidation?
Thomas Kolivakis: Bye.
Thomas Kolivakis: Persuasion is… Plus 11, and intimidation, that's 3.
george: You should be persuaded.
Kostadis Roussos: So you're gonna try to… you're gonna help him? You're gonna help him so he has advantage?
george: Yep.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright. Zephyr.
Kostadis Roussos: You're prone, you've got a… you've got a creature with a double-headed axe sitting over you, sort of, you know, you're Cretan, like, standing there ready to… and looking at you very hungry.
Kostadis Roussos: What do you… are you gonna try to persuade it that, you know, there's new management? Are you gonna try to tell it? Yes. Like, okay, you're gonna try to persuade it new management?
Thomas Kolivakis: We are different.
Kostadis Roussos: You're different?
Thomas Kolivakis: Oh my god.
Thomas Kolivakis: Do I have advantage?
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, you do.
Thomas Kolivakis: 20 to 21.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: The creature is wary and looks at you.
Thomas Kolivakis: Whoa.
Thomas Kolivakis: Look… We will leave you here.
Thomas Kolivakis: You will get your… I don't know, don't they see humans?
Kostadis Roussos: He eats, what does a mini… well, what does a minotaur eat? Generally, a minotaur eats, sacrifices from Athens, but in the absence of a sacrifice…
Kostadis Roussos: What is it gonna be?
Thomas Kolivakis: Exactly.
Kostadis Roussos: What is he doing?
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, what does a minotaur do?
Kostadis Roussos: So… so the Minotaur…
Kostadis Roussos: So the Minotaur, now that he's sort of calmed down, do you guys, you guys give it some food from your backpacks?
Nicholas Roussos: Yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright. He starts to eat the food.
Kostadis Roussos: Finally, he calms down just enough, like, he… right?
Kostadis Roussos: It goes… What does he do? He says, Hmm.
Kostadis Roussos: Bandits.
Kostadis Roussos: Men in black sloaks, come here.
Kostadis Roussos: And attack Minotaur.
Thomas Kolivakis: This will stop.
Kostadis Roussos: Hmm.
Kostadis Roussos: We'll stop!
Thomas Kolivakis: All alone.
Kostadis Roussos: Good.
Kostadis Roussos: He pauses. He looks at you, Zephyr, says, No hard feelings?
Thomas Kolivakis: No hard cheating.
Kostadis Roussos: He goes, hmm… well, this is not my room.
Kostadis Roussos: I stand guard.
Nicholas Roussos: 5 meters delivered.
Kostadis Roussos: As long as food keep coming.
Kostadis Roussos: And no more bandit come and attack.
Thomas Kolivakis: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: But he pauses. If bandit come attack, I find you, I kill you, I eat you.
Thomas Kolivakis: Yes.
Thomas Kolivakis: Promise.
Kostadis Roussos: You, you promise?
Thomas Kolivakis: Whoa.
Kostadis Roussos: Calmer, of course, then steps in and says, I don't mean to be rude or anything.
Kostadis Roussos: Calmer's gonna ask for something. You're gonna have to convince him to not ask for it, or you're gonna have to see what happens.
Thomas Kolivakis: So I… I bring Calmer to my side.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Thomas Kolivakis: Don't ask for anything.
Kostadis Roussos: goes, but I'm in charge here, I need to make sure that he understands the new rulership arrangements, that there's a new high clarity.
Thomas Kolivakis: But he is not very smart, and he will want to eat us, so…
Thomas Kolivakis: I think it's smarter to let it be.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, but are you sure?
Thomas Kolivakis: I will tell him on my own time.
Kostadis Roussos: Well, right, as long as you make sure to make absolutely sure that he knows that there is a new clerical order with the High Lord Master Calmer.
Thomas Kolivakis: Not at all.
Kostadis Roussos: Excellent.
Kostadis Roussos: You will?
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, excellent. And by the way, where do you intend to find bodies for this creature?
Nicholas Roussos: There's probably a bunch left over from the battles.
Thomas Kolivakis: We'll bring some people into the cult, into the temple, and they'll wander around.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, I see, we're going to bring sacrifices for the Minotaur. Excellent, I think that's a fantastic idea.
Thomas Kolivakis: Yo.
Kostadis Roussos: Zinnia Role and Insight Check.
george: Reset.
Kostadis Roussos: So…
george: 20.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, that's a very weird thing for a cleric of St. Cuthbert to say.
Kostadis Roussos: St. Cuthbert, just so you know, is a fanatically, is one of those gods that's, you know, very lawful good.
Nicholas Roussos: Whaa?
Nicholas Roussos: Calm, are you feeling okay?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, why, why wouldn't I be feeling okay? I'm absolute… this is… I… I'm… it's… it's just, I, I just am, just enjoying my new role as High Cleric of the Temple of Earth.
Kostadis Roussos: Do you know how much… he pauses and goes, you know, I started off as a cleric of St. Cuthbert, and I'm still very much… and I understand, you know, St. Cuthbert promised me all these things. What did I get? I got killed. And who saved me? A tiefling.
Kostadis Roussos: Not the cleric of… not the high cleric, not my order, but a tiefling, and, he looks at you, and a spy with a scarred face.
Kostadis Roussos: and a rogue. They were willing to go into my temple and pay the fee to raise me from the dead. They were willing to sacrifice themselves so that I wouldn't have my body mutilated, so I could be raised for the dead. It kind of puts a different spin on all the religious doctrine that I've been fed my whole life.
Kostadis Roussos: I just, you know, I've come to the realization that loyalty is a two-way street, and you have demonstrated loyalty, and I will demonstrate loyalty to you. As for St. Cuthbert and I, we have a good working relationship.
Thomas Kolivakis: Good.
Thomas Kolivakis: But…
Kostadis Roussos: There's something to be said about… there's something to be said about the slave's devotion of evil cultists to their high cleric.
Thomas Kolivakis: You liked it?
Kostadis Roussos: well, that like isn't the word I would like to use. I would simply say that after my experiences with the Canon
Kostadis Roussos: Terjon of Hommlet, and how he was willing to let me be dead, and did nothing to save me, and that the people he dismissed and I've been raised to dismiss were willing to save my skin, simply because I was their ally. It's kind of put a different perspective on my view on the religious
Kostadis Roussos: On the religious order.
Thomas Kolivakis: Question.
Thomas Kolivakis: I'll mull it over.
Kostadis Roussos: So, like, it's not… now, again, I am not saying that I am all of a sudden an evil… evil cleric of the earth god, but there's something to be said for the material that I've been reading. It does put a different perspective on the endless prattle of St. Cuthbert.
Thomas Kolivakis: Okay.
Thomas Kolivakis: That's good.
Kostadis Roussos: It's good to know. Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, to the north.
Thomas Kolivakis: Yes.
Kostadis Roussos: Let me just make a note here.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, so…
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, so, you arrive over here.
Kostadis Roussos: There is a… Skies are no longer here.
Kostadis Roussos: Right.
Kostadis Roussos: You arrive in this, hallway, and let me just make sure…
Kostadis Roussos: What do you think so.
Kostadis Roussos: Right.
Kostadis Roussos: This, stairway goes up.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright. Can you see that pin, by the way?
Kostadis Roussos: Did you see a pin? That's a steroid that goes.
Thomas Kolivakis: Got you, yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, cool.
Kostadis Roussos: That's a new feature they added. Very happy.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, do you go upstairs or keep, looking around?
Thomas Kolivakis: Wait… We came down to consolidate the territory.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, so, presumably you're gonna keep going, you're gonna keep,
Thomas Kolivakis: Yeah, let's keep looking at Bitty.
Kostadis Roussos: Right.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, so, okay, so…
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: So you see a door to the south.
Kostadis Roussos: And a passageway, and you also see the remains of the battle, which is a pile of water and steam.
Kostadis Roussos: That's what that blue thing is supposed to indicate.
Kostadis Roussos: That's,
Kostadis Roussos: So, what would you like to do? There's a passageway going east, north, and I don't think you guys explored the area to the south.
Thomas Kolivakis: Let's go… North.
Kostadis Roussos: North?
Thomas Kolivakis: Yes.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: The one thing you do know is that there is a… somewhere in the second level, the, whatchamacallit?
Kostadis Roussos: the,
Kostadis Roussos: the Fire Temple, the Greater Temple has, assets, so you don't know where that is yet, just keep that in mind.
Thomas Kolivakis: Greater Temple.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, you know that because when the battle ended, they suddenly showed up.
Kostadis Roussos: From all sorts of locations indicating that they had been here, that they weren't… that you're… there are…
Kostadis Roussos: They have forces deployed in the second level.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: There's a door to the east and a passageway to the west. Which way would you like to go?
Nicholas Roussos: ETH.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, one second.
Kostadis Roussos: Eastern.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, let's do one thing…
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah. East, you said, right?
Thomas Kolivakis: Yeah, no, we… yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: Nope.
Kostadis Roussos: Right.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, so you open this doorway to the east, okay.
Kostadis Roussos: That is what I read, that's 239.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, this large chamber is evidently used for storing wooden lumber. Stacks of firewood stand near the
Kostadis Roussos: Entrance… planks and beams at several wet sands. Just inside the entry are large, lumpy sacks. Apparently, this is a storeroom, so now you know where you guys store the firewood. Which, I guess, if you're… I guess if you're the chief of operations is important.
Thomas Kolivakis: It's good to know. Let's go right.
Thomas Kolivakis: East.
Kostadis Roussos: Yep.
Kostadis Roussos: Store room.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, to the right.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, first of all, who can pick the lock?
Thomas Kolivakis: Sequoia. Not me.
Nicholas Roussos: I can, yeah, I have thief's tools.
Kostadis Roussos: You have? Alright, try to pick the lock.
Nicholas Roussos: Will, 33 work?
Kostadis Roussos: I'm not sure, let me check.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, you're able to…
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Right.
Kostadis Roussos: You rolled a 33, right?
Nicholas Roussos: Yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: Right.
Kostadis Roussos: So this is another storeroom. You're beginning to realize that the temple… beginning to realize that the temple is well-supplied.
Kostadis Roussos: Right. You're also beginning to realize that being the big bad at the end of the game means that you also have to handle supplies and boring things like equipment. It's not, you know, raping and pillaging and destroying villages and accumulating.
Thomas Kolivakis: We'll order some, we'll get some other guys to do this.
Kostadis Roussos: Like, just, you know, it's like, this,
Kostadis Roussos: But you do find a whole bunch of theirs. Chainmail armor, plate armor, backpacks, holy water, lanterns, lockpicks…
Kostadis Roussos: Mirrors, parchments, pouches, ropes, sacks, spikes, tinder boxes.
Kostadis Roussos: If anybody needs an upgrade in their armor, Calmer doesn't.
george: Oh, no.
Kostadis Roussos: Those, yes.
Kostadis Roussos: What?
george: Zoom is the right room.
george: This one? Yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: Stores.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: And so, if you ever need anything like this, Let me just put this…
Kostadis Roussos: Alright. Okay. Oh.
Kostadis Roussos: Good to know that, the… so, Zephyr, you've decided you need to hire… you need to put somebody in charge of this?
Kostadis Roussos: You know, that's what a good second-in-command is for.
Thomas Kolivakis: Yes.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: You know, Chief of operations, you're more big ideas, big, big, big ideas kind of thing, right?
Kostadis Roussos: Let's see…
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, I understand.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, so, down the hallway?
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, so one of the things you do remember at this point in time as you're looking at the map, Zephyr, is there's still the three prisoners that, are still stuck in, over here.
Thomas Kolivakis: Where?
Kostadis Roussos: Here, I'm about to do it,
Kostadis Roussos: Just to make sure I got the right room… 2.35… So… ignores it.
Kostadis Roussos: But not… no, sorry, I take it back.
Kostadis Roussos: Prisoners…
Kostadis Roussos: Oh yeah, they were there. Yep.
Kostadis Roussos: Prisoners.
Kostadis Roussos: You… you… this is where you… you found one of… one of… this is where you found one of the prisoners, from the Earth Temple, or one of the temples that was supposed to be sacrificed. You freed one of them, but you haven't freed the other three.
Thomas Kolivakis: And worthy?
Kostadis Roussos: There, I just put the pin.
Thomas Kolivakis: Oh, here. Okay, we'll do the loop here.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: You know, just keep that in mind.
Kostadis Roussos: Calmer does observe that, you know, we do have a feeding problem.
Thomas Kolivakis: Meeting from.
Kostadis Roussos: Well, we have a minotaur, it needs food.
Thomas Kolivakis: Oh, boy.
Kostadis Roussos: We have prisoners.
Thomas Kolivakis: If they're a bad character, I'll…
Kostadis Roussos: There you go, so just… I just want to point out that we could solve two birds with one stone.
Kostadis Roussos: And don't forget, we are now the evil overlords of this temple. Freeing good people is not exactly something we would be doing.
Nicholas Roussos: Are you trying to get your cleric abilities taken away, or…
Kostadis Roussos: Sequoia, my dear boy. He looks at you and goes, This is a common misconception that the various orthodoxies of the various religions like to present. But once you reach a certain level of power as a cleric, that power is intrinsic to you as a cleric.
Nicholas Roussos: You are not that powerful yet.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, yes I am.
Kostadis Roussos: But, have no fear, it is not my intention. I… St. Guthrid and I have had a conversation, and we've agreed that my continued integration into the temple is a necessary part of our plans to defeat it.
Kostadis Roussos: At this point, Frostbrand pipes up. Hey, Sequoia, isn't this what we discussed about our plants here, that we're going to be sneakety-sneakity?
Nicholas Roussos: Yeah, it looks like somebody, though, is forgetting about it.
Thomas Kolivakis: That's true.
Kostadis Roussos: Just as a…
Thomas Kolivakis: Trevor, trust that?
Kostadis Roussos: It's, like, the more days you spend with Calmer as the boss, the more likely bad things happen, just keep that in mind.
Thomas Kolivakis: So we should attack as soon as possible.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, like, I'm just saying, like, the more days he spends as the boss, The more he,
Kostadis Roussos: Thinks, hmm, maybe being the boss is the good idea.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Or maybe you need to go outside. This place evidently held once many stores of supplies. Much of the foodstuffs are now scattered in ruin, rotting on the table. Rotting… broken containers are tossed about with many mixed temples, you know.
Kostadis Roussos: Calmer looks at it, looks at you, Zephyr, and says.
Kostadis Roussos: Well, I think we'll have to talk to Lucius about re-cleaning this mess up. This is absolutely unacceptable.
Thomas Kolivakis: Impress?
Kostadis Roussos: What?
Thomas Kolivakis: Oh, here. Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Move.
Kostadis Roussos: Criticism.
Thomas Kolivakis: What's the, no, what's the new car?
Kostadis Roussos: The Broken Blades. Yeah, the Broken Blades. Do you think they're the right ones to have this come?
Thomas Kolivakis: Yes.
Kostadis Roussos: I think so, too. What's his name? Do you think Dren Halveth will enjoy this kind of task?
Thomas Kolivakis: Yeah, he's… he's founded Manuel Lieberman.
Kostadis Roussos: Very well, very well. He pauses and thinks. Or perhaps we wish to give each one of these rooms to one of the three clerics. One to the Earth Temple, one to the water temple, one to the Water Temple, one to the air temple, and one to the Fire Temple. That way, they…
Nicholas Roussos: I see a water couple get two.
Kostadis Roussos: No one. I dived. He goes, I can't count.
Nicholas Roussos: Somebody didn't pass school.
Kostadis Roussos: Well, yes, I was too busy in my religious learnings. Did I ever tell you about the problem of the St. Cuthbert's educational systems and the schools that they employ, and the fact that they're all… they drill you from the minute you come in into the greatness of St. Cuthbert's?
Nicholas Roussos: Oh yeah, and how would the Earth Temple fix?
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, no, that's…
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, that's a great question. I haven't yet thought about a new educational system based off of the principles of the chaotic Temple of Earth. I've been thinking that perhaps…
Kostadis Roussos: But that's a great question, and he pulls out a little piece of scroll and starts scribbling.
Nicholas Roussos: Great, we've got to fill 5 minutes of silence.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, okay. So, I'm gonna put you guys back in this, in this area. Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: While this is happening.
Kostadis Roussos: Fairleman.
Kostadis Roussos: Well, this is happening.
Kostadis Roussos: Just because…
Kostadis Roussos: A very large and very disturbingly demented ghoul suddenly sees you as you come down this corridor and starts approaching you.
Kostadis Roussos: Moaning.
Kostadis Roussos: Zinnia, roll an insight check, or investigation, with advantage.
george: I'll do Insight.
Thomas Kolivakis: 45-minute timer started.
george: Okay, I've… I rolled a 1 in my first one.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
george: My second, 12th.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, I think… well, what you remember is that there was a necromancer who was raising the dead.
Kostadis Roussos: But, remember how all the ghouls showed up?
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, and apparently said Necromancer is still around and active.
Kostadis Roussos: And apparently, at Necromancer, has upped his game and is no longer just raising minor creatures, but far more deadly creatures. And so this… that's what you think about, just as the creature decides that, well.
Kostadis Roussos: You look… you are living. He is undead. This is an opportunity.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, roll for initiative, gentlemen.
Kostadis Roussos: Initiative?
Thomas Kolivakis: Yes.
Thomas Kolivakis: Wait, how do you do it inside the roll twin?
Kostadis Roussos: So what you do is you click your… just click your icon.
Kostadis Roussos: And then click Initiative, that's it.
Thomas Kolivakis: But… there's nowhere.
Kostadis Roussos: No, no, click inside of D&D Beyond Initiative, as normal, just click your icon first.
Thomas Kolivakis: Huh?
Kostadis Roussos: Go into Rule 20, click your icon.
Kostadis Roussos: And then click Initiative in D&D Beyond.
Thomas Kolivakis: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Were you able to get it done?
Thomas Kolivakis: Go to work.
Kostadis Roussos: I see a 21. Is that your initiative?
Thomas Kolivakis: No, mine's 19.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, well, fine, didn't work, let me… that doesn't matter. Alright, Zinnia, your initiative?
Kostadis Roussos: Zinnia? Initiative.
Kostadis Roussos: George?
Nicholas Roussos: Yep, finishing.
Kostadis Roussos: Initi… initiative.
george: I, I rolled the papers.
Nicholas Roussos: Planning fruit.
george: I wrote… oh.
Kostadis Roussos: Enroll.
george: It didn't show.
Kostadis Roussos: No, it did not.
Kostadis Roussos: Just tell me what… tell me the number.
george: It was 12. No, it logged me out of TNGBM.
george: There you go.
george: Yeah, it was… It was 12.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, Sequoia, you're up first.
Nicholas Roussos: Alright?
Nicholas Roussos: Where is it?
Kostadis Roussos: You should sit down to the south.
Nicholas Roussos: There it is.
Nicholas Roussos: I do not have enough range to get to it, so I'm gonna sit here and shoot an arrow at it.
Kostadis Roussos: Well, I mean, the other thing you could do is hide and let it come to you.
Nicholas Roussos: So I'm just gonna poke my head around the corner, shootin' narrow.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Roll your… you roll your stealth just to see if you successfully hide?
Nicholas Roussos: Oh yeah, stealth. I hate with the shortbow, and… I am hidden.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh yeah, you are definitely.
Nicholas Roussos: Now, keep in mind, I am at the point, I have a plus 13 to all the deck stuff.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, so basically we're just rolling a D1 to see if you rolled a 1.
Nicholas Roussos: Yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: And since you're a halfling, you have to roll twice a 1, right?
Nicholas Roussos: Yep.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Nicholas Roussos: Oh, 10 plus the damage, I don't get a sneak attack.
Kostadis Roussos: They do.
Nicholas Roussos: Oh yeah, I do, 29.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, Zephyr, you're up.
Kostadis Roussos: Remember, he hasn't yet attacked, so you get your assassin's advantage.
Thomas Kolivakis: Too far from you to talk him.
Kostadis Roussos: I mean, you could use your ranged weapon.
Thomas Kolivakis: Yup. I don't do that.
Thomas Kolivakis: My pistol.
Kostadis Roussos: Oops.
Thomas Kolivakis: That's why I roll natural ones, so nice.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Thomas Kolivakis: Second attack?
Kostadis Roussos: I can't see your die rolls, so just tell me what you rolled.
Thomas Kolivakis: I rolled a 19.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Thomas Kolivakis: And then, one damage.
Kostadis Roussos: Don't forget yours, you get your bonuses.
Kostadis Roussos: As an assassin.
Thomas Kolivakis: 5d6?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, and there's an assassination bonus.
Thomas Kolivakis: Oh, wait, yeah, let me find that.
Thomas Kolivakis: That's not okay.
Thomas Kolivakis: Well, in total, $30.
Kostadis Roussos: 30 damage.
Thomas Kolivakis: About 31 damage total.
Kostadis Roussos: 31.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: The ghoul still thinks you're tasty food.
Kostadis Roussos: Marches up to Calmer.
Kostadis Roussos: Let's see what happens, okay.
Kostadis Roussos: So… Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, okay, so that's your start your turn, so this doesn't start your turn.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, so the ghoul… He texts me up.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, so he takes a bite on Calmer.
Kostadis Roussos: Why doesn't it know how to, like… why can't it do attacks? Okay, so… D10.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, that is an attack. Oh, I haven't rolled for that much. Okay, that's a… that definitely hits calmer.
Kostadis Roussos: And Calmer takes 21 points of damage.
Kostadis Roussos: And must make a saving throw.
Kostadis Roussos: What is the saving throw against, DC-10 Constitution?
Kostadis Roussos: And, what happens?
Kostadis Roussos: No. It's, 7, so he's poisoned. He's knocked out.
Kostadis Roussos: He is, what is he?
Kostadis Roussos: Paralyzed. So Calmer is paralyzed.
Kostadis Roussos: Right.
Kostadis Roussos: The creature takes a swipe at Sequoia.
Kostadis Roussos: What's your armor class, Sequoia?
Nicholas Roussos: My armor class is… 15, sorry.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, roll… roll is sitting, throw.
Nicholas Roussos: What saving throw?
Kostadis Roussos: Constitution DC-10. DC-10.
Nicholas Roussos: Not 20.
Kostadis Roussos: You are not paralyzed.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, but you still take damage.
Kostadis Roussos: 8 points of damage.
Kostadis Roussos: Me? Alright, yeah, 8 points of damage.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, the creature steps over, pushes… steps over calmer, and tax, I guess, Zinnia.
Kostadis Roussos: With his claw.
Kostadis Roussos: Zinnia, what's your armor class?
george: Thank you.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, that is a miss.
Kostadis Roussos: Hold on. Calmer has a Ring of Evasion. Rings of evasion have important properties.
Kostadis Roussos: Ring of reaction.
Kostadis Roussos: So that magic… No, unfortunately, it's not magic.
Kostadis Roussos: That's an ability. Alright. Alright, Zinnia, you're up.
george: While the pack, I guess.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
george: What's armor class?
Kostadis Roussos: It's… The time for class is 14.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, hold on. Roll a constitution saving throw.
george: Constitution ends up?
Kostadis Roussos: Yep.
george: Going through it, natural tweet.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, you notice that it stinks a lot, and that that stench has caused… would have poisoned you, but…
Kostadis Roussos: You, your mask and your training as a spy allowed you to escape it, just in time.
george: Good.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Or more to the point, you've smelled… you've smelled and tasted worse things in your life. Alright, do your attacks?
george: I did… 19 points of damage.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
george: How many headwoods do you still have?
Kostadis Roussos: 65?
george: Y'all, I'll use a bonus.
Kostadis Roussos: Right.
george: And…
george: I do 21 more points of damage, so 4…
Kostadis Roussos: 21 points for… 21 points for damage, alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, Calmer needs to roll a saving throw, see if he's not still paralyzed.
Kostadis Roussos: He's still paralyzed. Sequoia, you're up.
Kostadis Roussos: First roll… first roll a saving throw against its stench.
Nicholas Roussos: the Constitution?
Kostadis Roussos: You blow it.
Kostadis Roussos: So you are… you have the poisoned condition?
Kostadis Roussos: Which means you need to roll… you roll with disadvantage.
Nicholas Roussos: Great.
Nicholas Roussos: How much HP did this thing have left?
Kostadis Roussos: How much HP is at 44?
Nicholas Roussos: The 15 hit?
Kostadis Roussos: 15, you just… 15, let me just see… yes, it does hit, in fact.
Nicholas Roussos: Alright, I still love this advantage, though.
Nicholas Roussos: Damn it! 14.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, so, yeah, you don't get your sneak attack bonus.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Nicholas Roussos: And I miss.
Kostadis Roussos: You missed? Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: But no, both of those attacks hit. 15 and a 14, it has an armor cost of 14.
Nicholas Roussos: 31 points of damage.
Kostadis Roussos: Total?
Nicholas Roussos: Yeah, on that attack.
Kostadis Roussos: Well, no, you don't get your sneak attack bonus, because you're attacking with disadvantage.
Nicholas Roussos: Is that really how it works?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
Kostadis Roussos: Let me just.
Nicholas Roussos: What's your golden.
Kostadis Roussos: Let me just check, let me just check, you just… you just… I actually don't know.
Kostadis Roussos: Does Sneak Attack.
Kostadis Roussos: Work if you have disadvantage.
Kostadis Roussos: No, yeah, it does not work if you have disadvantage.
Nicholas Roussos: Great.
Nicholas Roussos: So I'm understanding…
Kostadis Roussos: How much? 11?
Nicholas Roussos: That's my dagger.
Nicholas Roussos: After all, I looked.
Nicholas Roussos: I have to roll one more time, sorry.
Nicholas Roussos: Yeah, hit. For…
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Nicholas Roussos: 20 in total.
Kostadis Roussos: 20 in total? So you did…
Kostadis Roussos: Great, 24.
Nicholas Roussos: I'm gonna deal 20 points of damage, please.
Kostadis Roussos: Got 24, alright. Zephyr Europe.
Thomas Kolivakis: He's gonna die now.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: First roll your… first roll of the saving throw.
Thomas Kolivakis: Dexterity? What is…
Kostadis Roussos: Constitution.
Thomas Kolivakis: Got it.
Thomas Kolivakis: Roll the 13.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, you are not poison… You are poisoned.
Thomas Kolivakis: I'm poisoned.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, you are poisoned.
Thomas Kolivakis: That's great.
Thomas Kolivakis: Do I have a disadvantage?
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, disadvantage. On ability checks and attack rolls.
Thomas Kolivakis: 45 advantage and disadvantage.
Kostadis Roussos: It cancels out.
Thomas Kolivakis: Okay, so…
Kostadis Roussos: And just in case you're all wondering, it is not Magic the Gathering rules. One disadvantage, one advantage.
Kostadis Roussos: they don't… Keep flipping until you make a decision.
Thomas Kolivakis: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: If you play Magic the Gathering, you have these spells where you keep dropping cards until they find, like, you know, there's a stack of 30 cards, and then you figure out what the hell happened.
Thomas Kolivakis: It's been too long since I played.
Thomas Kolivakis: Yeah, apparently.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, okay, so you have disadvantage.
Thomas Kolivakis: So I rolled at 26. But, do I still have Sneak Attack?
Kostadis Roussos: That's what we just established.
Thomas Kolivakis: Oh, okay.
Thomas Kolivakis: I asked Arrow 26 to hit…
Kostadis Roussos: Did you roll it with disadvantage?
Thomas Kolivakis: Yeah, no, with, nothing.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, 26, yes, okay, that is a hit, is Armor Class 14.
Thomas Kolivakis: And I rolled 9 damage.
Kostadis Roussos: H.
Kostadis Roussos: Alrighty.
Kostadis Roussos: the ghoul.
Kostadis Roussos: Ghoul is still alive. Barely still alive.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: It, attempts to bite Sequoia and misses.
Kostadis Roussos: It strikes with its claws, and misses it.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, and strikes with its claws again, wow.
Kostadis Roussos: Wow, I rolled some…
Kostadis Roussos: Why does it minus 2?
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, doesn't matter. All of these would have missed. Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Ghoul, Ghoul, the Ghoul, gomez, Zinnia.
Kostadis Roussos: You're up.
george: No effect.
george: I'm going to do another constitution check now.
Kostadis Roussos: No, because you, you made it, you are immune to ghoul… the… the ghoul, poison until later.
Kostadis Roussos: Until after your next long rest.
george: What's the ZRA class again?
Kostadis Roussos: 14.
george: Yes.
george: And it hadn't.
george: Lanquist damage.
Kostadis Roussos: 9 points of damage, right?
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
george: Is that it?
george: I'll do it.
george: Bonus…
george: I do… 9 more potent damage, 18 minutes.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: He's dead.
Kostadis Roussos: Yep.
Kostadis Roussos: You search his body.
Kostadis Roussos: I presume?
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, let me just make sure there's something that happens here.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: He… you find a note on the corpse.
Thomas Kolivakis: Yes.
Kostadis Roussos: Addressed to the four of you.
Thomas Kolivakis: Really?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
Kostadis Roussos: Saying… something to… saying, and it says, to the interlopers and thieves of my home.
Kostadis Roussos: Thank you for this harvest of death.
Kostadis Roussos: I shall… even if this creature doesn't kill you, eventually one of them will.
Thomas Kolivakis: We are being attacked.
Kostadis Roussos: You make a role… a role in insight or investigation check.
Kostadis Roussos: Calmer rolls with a D20 plus 11.
george: I rolled 21.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, you remember something very interesting all of a sudden, Zinnia.
Thomas Kolivakis: Oh, natural 20.
Kostadis Roussos: Right. Zinnia and… okay, so here's what you immediately figure out. Zinnia remembers that Romag muttered that the undead
Kostadis Roussos: In the first… on the first level, no longer reported to him.
Kostadis Roussos: That somehow… remember how you guys went and fought all these undead, that all, you know, Romag was bitching about how they no longer reported to him, and they no longer listened to him?
Kostadis Roussos: What that implies is they used to listen to somebody.
Thomas Kolivakis: Yes.
Kostadis Roussos: And that… what Zephyr has figured out is that there may… that somebody may have been allied with Barkinar. Remember, Barkinar was the old… was the old head of the Temple of Elemental Evil… of Earth. He gets promoted to the Upper Temple, right?
Kostadis Roussos: Hartsch, Romag becomes the new head of the Earth Temple.
Kostadis Roussos: Right? Hartsch becomes his number 2.
Kostadis Roussos: You guys killed both of them, right?
Thomas Kolivakis: No, where's Barkinar?
Kostadis Roussos: Well, Barkinar… Barkinar's down in the bottom levels. He's the one who's giving you the homework assignments?
Kostadis Roussos: Right. Well, it turns out there may… now you're beginning to realize there was somebody else who could have had the job that Romag had.
Kostadis Roussos: And that somebody else is a necromancer.
Thomas Kolivakis: Which… There's a new Earth Temple deck.
Kostadis Roussos: No, there… so again…
Kostadis Roussos: Barkinar… so just… here's what you figure out. Barkinar used to be the head of the Earth Temple, alright?
Kostadis Roussos: He gets promoted to the upper temple.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, Romag fills his job.
Kostadis Roussos: When you guys show up in the temple, Romag's the current head of the Earth Temple, alright?
Thomas Kolivakis: Yup, yeah, yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: As you guys went around, you know, working for Romag, you defeated a whole bunch of undead creatures, do you remember that?
Kostadis Roussos: One of the things you'll remember is that Romag said, damn it, the earth… the ghouls and zombies and undead no longer listen to him.
Kostadis Roussos: At the time, you kind of were like, yeah, whatever, right?
Kostadis Roussos: Now you realize that
Kostadis Roussos: when Barkinar… when Romag got promoted, there was somebody else who worked for the Earth Temple.
Thomas Kolivakis: And it was appointed by Barkinar?
Kostadis Roussos: You don't know, it was like… maybe Romag didn't…
Kostadis Roussos: clean up his own mess. Maybe Romag took the job and… The necromancer escaped. Who knows?
Kostadis Roussos: But that necromancer, who was the old, thought the job belonged to him, now thinks that you guys don't deserve the job.
Kostadis Roussos: And you've basically created a dumpster fire of dead bodies for him to create and continuously attack you with.
Thomas Kolivakis: We will have to be on our toes.
Kostadis Roussos: Right? That's the important point. So, like, there was a… and he's now basically… he's now arrogant enough to have dropped the note, put a note on one of his creations.
Kostadis Roussos: Telling you that, you know, if you find this note, let it be known that you are… you aren't qualified to be the head of the Earth Temple.
Kostadis Roussos: that… I mean, it goes on as Calmer picks up the note and goes, my god, this person's busy. It goes on to describe how Calmer is a disgrace, and that he's not qualified to be the head of the Earth Temple, and that, you know, he can see through him, and his approach to the rituals is all wrong.
Thomas Kolivakis: Alright.
Thomas Kolivakis: Whoa.
Thomas Kolivakis: We'll find this guy, somehow.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes. Something… something for you guys to keep in mind. All right.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: So there's a… there is a… you know, as I said, being the head… being the big bad at the end of the game is a little bit painful, because, you know, there's lots of other big bads. Alright, which way do you want to go? South?
Kostadis Roussos: Well, that's pretty much the only way you haven't explored yet. Or through the door over here, to the east.
george: healthiest.
Kostadis Roussos: South? Huh?
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, so there's a door over here, would you like to open it?
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Alrighty, okay, let's see, what's in this room?
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, this oddly shaped chamber is bisected by a curving wall of well-dressed, bordered stones.
Kostadis Roussos: The wall is about 4 feet tall, and to the south of it is water, high enough to almost flow over the top. Water trickles in from several places along the east, south, and west walls. Overflow gravitates so the floor drains, even as you watch.
Kostadis Roussos: Zephyr, you immediately recognize this for what it is, the water supply of the temple.
Kostadis Roussos: Or rather, the upper temple.
Kostadis Roussos: Of course, Calmer observes that the last time you thought you found a water supply, it turned out to be a creature from hell, so…
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, keep that out.
Thomas Kolivakis: Let me go in?
Kostadis Roussos: Ask your friend. Calmer's like game. The rest of you have to make a decision.
Kostadis Roussos: Sequoia?
Nicholas Roussos: Yeah, sure.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Is that for you walk in?
Kostadis Roussos: Amazingly, no creature, nothing attacks you, it's just cold, wet water.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: As you step on the… okay, roll an investigation check, Zephyr, before you step in.
Kostadis Roussos: Sorry.
Kostadis Roussos: Is that fair?
Thomas Kolivakis: Yes?
Kostadis Roussos: Role investigation?
Thomas Kolivakis: Terrible, also, 8.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, okay, so what happens is you slip, and you slide, and hit the wall over here, so you're kind of… you've been knocked prone.
Thomas Kolivakis: Thank you.
Kostadis Roussos: Around… you look around… And you realize that the floor is covered with a barely visible…
Kostadis Roussos: form algae. Quite slimy and slippery.
Thomas Kolivakis: Hmm.
Kostadis Roussos: And you also realize that there was a… the floor was sloping down. It was barely visible. But that's why you ended up sliding all the way down.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, what do the rest of you do?
Kostadis Roussos: Let's go. Zephyr, what do you do?
Kostadis Roussos: I'm sorry, Zinnia. Sequoia, sorry, Sequoia. Nick, what do you do?
Nicholas Roussos: Oh, what do I do,
Kostadis Roussos: So, just to recap, Zephyr stepped on the… he walked in the door, alright?
Nicholas Roussos: I'm gonna… if he's gonna get in the water supply, I'm gonna kinda just take a few steps back.
Kostadis Roussos: You're taking a few steps, but you're like, I've jumped into acidic pools one too many times.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, calmer.
Kostadis Roussos: Calmly takes a rope and throws it to Zephyr.
Thomas Kolivakis: Okay, I got that.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Zinnia, what do you do?
george: I'll let Calmer handle it.
Kostadis Roussos: You're gonna let Calmer handle it?
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, Zephyr, you're… you've got… you've got a rope.
Thomas Kolivakis: Oh.
Thomas Kolivakis: I'll pull my way to safety.
Kostadis Roussos: Do you want to look in the… do you want to look at the… by the way, the… as the… remember, there was a 4-foot wall, right? That was holding… as the water falls over, it is just water. Do you want to look inside?
Thomas Kolivakis: Okay, I'll take a peek.
Kostadis Roussos: We're gonna take a peek.
Kostadis Roussos: Alrighty, I'm gonna take up… Peak.
Kostadis Roussos: You take a peek.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: You see… A large, round, slime-covered object.
Thomas Kolivakis: I reach in the slime.
Kostadis Roussos: Well, it's, like, over, like, you'd have to jump into the water.
Kostadis Roussos: And swim down to there.
Thomas Kolivakis: Okay, I'll jump in with the rope.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright. You tie yourself and jump in with the rope.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: So, you're now… Sitting… you've now… you're… you're now in the water.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay. Unfortunately, you know how to swim, so that's good to know, and you're not exactly weighed down, so you're able to float. Do you want to take a dive into the water to see what's in there?
Thomas Kolivakis: Yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: You're gonna take a deep breath and go there?
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, you take a deep breath, and you discover there is a shield that is covered in slime on slime.
Thomas Kolivakis: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Do you want to try to pick it up?
Thomas Kolivakis: Yeah, pick it up.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, roll a sleight of hands or a strength check, whichever one you want.
Thomas Kolivakis: slit of that.
Thomas Kolivakis: Terrible rules. 11.
Kostadis Roussos: Or… 11. The sleight of hand fails, alright.
Kostadis Roussos: You're running out of air, so I presume you're going to reach up to the surface. Do you want to try again?
Thomas Kolivakis: Again, let's go.
Kostadis Roussos: You're gonna try…
Kostadis Roussos: Again. Alright, roll another sleight of hands, but as you go in, you realize your last one caused it to be just dislodged enough so that if you miss again, you'll lose whatever it is, whatever's there. It's become a little bit more tricky, so roll again.
Thomas Kolivakis: Come on.
Thomas Kolivakis: 13.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, you made it, just barely.
Kostadis Roussos: You made it just barely. Grabbing onto the shield, and you pull hard, it dislodges from the floor, and you're able to bring it up.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, you swim to the surface, and… alright, calmer, and you… is anybody gonna help Calmer, or are you guys gonna just rely on Calmer's strength to pull him forward?
george: All per hotel now.
Kostadis Roussos: You're gonna go help him? Alright, because you help him, no more checks are required, and you manage to acquire a magical shield plus 1.
Kostadis Roussos: So, does anybody need a shield?
Thomas Kolivakis: Shield.
Thomas Kolivakis: Okay, so…
Kostadis Roussos: Fortunately, you haven't shipped.
george: it.
Kostadis Roussos: Fortunately, you have a cleric who can use shields.
george: Hmm.
Kostadis Roussos: I don't know, just add it to the brain.
Kostadis Roussos: He goes, very well done.
Kostadis Roussos: That was very well done. I cannot stress so much. Calmer's very happy that you've, managed
Kostadis Roussos: To, get him a new shield.
Thomas Kolivakis: No worries, Calmer, I'm here for you.
Kostadis Roussos: He knows. He's very happy.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, okay, just watch that one. Okay. All right.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, and we will stop here for today.
Kostadis Roussos: But there was one more thing…
Kostadis Roussos: I wonder if that happened today.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, that's good. We're good.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, hold on. There was one more thing that I should tell you that I forgot to tell you.
Kostadis Roussos: Since you did not kill the Minotaur, that was my bad.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, the Minotaur, one of the things you realize that the Minotaur, as it was mumbling to you, right?
Kostadis Roussos: Had seen the undead creatures you guys are talking about.
Kostadis Roussos: Like, some of the bandits it was referring to, you now realize were undead.
Thomas Kolivakis: So… He can eat the undead.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, but it prefers fresh meat to undead meat.
Kostadis Roussos: you know.
Kostadis Roussos: 7 innocent… 7 innocent children from a remote city are preferable, but, you know…
Kostadis Roussos: You can't… beggars can't be pickers.
Thomas Kolivakis: That's true.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, folks.
Kostadis Roussos: So yes, there is a necromancer who apparently feels that he owes… you owe him a job.
george: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, guys.
Kostadis Roussos: I hope you enjoyed yourselves. I enjoyed myself. See you next week, I hope.
george: But…
Kostadis Roussos: Bye-bye. Good night.
Thomas Kolivakis: Great, good.